

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT & DIGITAL MARKETING

CONTACT



+1 605 759 4737



jamesnguyen99@hotmail.com



South Dakota, USA



jamesvincentnguyen.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science

Computer Science

University of South Dakota 2018 – 2022 | *GPA 3.85*

Bachelor of Business

Marketing

University of South Dakota 2018 – 2022

SKILLS

- Java
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Python
- REST API
- SQL

SOFTWARE

- NetBeans | IDE
- Visual Studio | IDE
- MySQL Workbench | IDE
- GitHub | Version Control
- Adobe Photoshop | Graphics
- Adobe Illustrator | Graphics
- DaVinci Resolve | Video
- Microsoft Office

PROFILE

An aspiring software developer and digital marketer with 2+ years of professional experience helping grow online brands through the designing, developing, and deploying of online storefronts and marketing campaigns. Eager to learn, grow, and assist teams in developing meaningful projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital Marketing & Web Support Specialist

Weisser Distributing | 06/2022 - PRESENT

- Collaborated with Brand Manager to develop and deploy email automation flows and campaigns
- Designed creatives using Photoshop, Illustrator, and Davinci Resolve to be used in marketing campaigns
- Analyzed weekly performance metrics to determine advertisement adjustments using Google Ads, Meta Ads, and Amazon Seller Central
- Designed and deployed several on-brand online storefronts

FC Goods Intern

Weisser Distributing | 05/2021 - 06/2022

- Developed product customization experiences and web page enhancing modules using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery
- Successfully deployed web enhancements that standardized the process for custom orders resulting in workflow efficiencies
- Communicated and collaborated with department leads to define project timeline and scope
- Designed and sourced product packaging elements to enhance brand image and develop brand loyalty

PROJECTS

Web Automation Applications

Java | REST API | SQL

- Developed a series of Java applications to automate browser tasks
- Designed and deployed a relational database using MySQL
- Designed and coded REST API to communicate with applications using Java and Apache Tomcat

Online Portfolio Website

HTML | JavaScript | CSS

- Utilized HTML, JavaScript, and CSS to develop a personal portfolio website to showcase skills and work experience
- Implemented animated features using JavaScript and CSS keyframes to create a more engaging site